# **Darshan Patel**

Edison, NJ • +1 848-235-8321 • patel7darshan97@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/imdp7 • https://patelsportfolio.netlify.app/

# **Software Development Engineer**

4+ years of experience. Transformed web applications at Martketcol, increasing efficiency by 20% and improving functionalities by 50% in 9 months. Enhanced user engagement with a 30% faster load time, resulting in a 15% decrease in bounce rate. At Clearpool Group, reduced API response times by 50%, leading to a 20% increase in user satisfaction. Collaborated on refactoring legacy code, reducing errors by 40% in under a year.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Software Development Engineer • Full-time

June 2023 - Present

#### Clearpool Group, BMO Capital Tradings

New York

Worked and developed web components to improve the usage into multiple use case. Worked on server side i.e, Java Spring to accommodate front end compatibility with different environments and cherry-picking commits to release branches for QA testing. Maintaining code structure and writing Jest and Junit unit test to test and deploy the changes on jenkins.

- Implemented new caching mechanism, reducing API response times by 50%, resulting in a 20% increase in user satisfaction and a 15% decrease in server costs.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to refactor legacy code, reducing system errors by 40% and improving overall
  application stability.
- Optimized code base, resulting in a 30% improvement in application performance, leading to faster response times and enhanced user experience.
- Delivered 5 new features ahead of schedule, resulting in increased customer satisfaction and a 20% boost in user engagement.

## Front End Engineer

**September 2019 - June 2020** 

#### **Martketcol Apprenticeship**

Newark, NJ, USA

- Designed Dashboard components and testing methods to increase the efficiency of application by 20%.
   Revamped 30 web components using JavaScript (ES6), Typescript, React.js 18.0, Redux, Rest API's, JQuery and designing tools improve functionalities by 50%.
   Unit, Integration Testing, using Jest and Cypress with CI/CD pipelines to maintain quality with peers.
   Refactoring code for maintaining and scalability of the application, providing additional perspective reviewing code.
- Improved website load time by 30% through optimization techniques, resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement and a 15% decrease in bounce rate.

## Front End/Ui Developer Apprenticeship

**January 2019 - May 2019** 

**Sun Trust Bank** 

Atlanta, GA, USA

• Assisted in building beautiful UI for clients without compromising functionality for aesthetics. • Unit testing in Jest to ensure code was 100% bug free.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Masters In Computer Science**

New Jersey Institute Of Technology

Newark, NJ, USA • January 2019 - May 2022

## **PROJECTS**

Yahoo Finance November 2023 - Present

Demo:-https://yhfinance.netlify.app/

Build a MERN stack real time yahoo finance SPA using websockets, external marketdata API's - finnhub.io, financialmodelingprep, RapidAPI and payment Stripe API. Automation Testing using selenium and deployment using netlify for frontend and cyclic for node,js and mongoDB cluster for database.

AWS Console November 2022 - Present

Demo:-https://awsui.netlify.app/

Authentication - AWS Cognito (AWS pool), UI Library - AWS Design (Cloudscape), Backend - Node.js, Redux Store, Payments and billing through Stripe.js API - Validation of cards and banks

- Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud
- · Amazon Web Services
- Application
   Programming
   Interface
- · AWS Amplify
- Aws Management Console
- Cascading Style Sheet
- · Code Refactoring
- Commitment
- Communication
- Computer Program
- Computer Science
- Content Distribution Network
- Cryptography
- Data Storage
- Data Visualization
- Dbeaver

- DevOps Operations
- Distributed Computing
- Firebase
- Forecasting
- Git
- GitHub
  - GitLab
- Google Cloud Platform
- GraphQL
- High Availability
- Hypertext Markup Language
- Integration Testing
- Interpersonal Skills
- Java
- Java
- JavaScript
- JavaScript Object Notation

- Jenkins
- jQuery
- JUnit
- Key Management
- Kubernetes
- Linear Programming
- Linux
- · Microsoft Azure
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Office
- Microsoft PowerPoint
- Microsoft SQL Server
- MySQL
- Next.js
- Node.JS
- Nonlinear Programming
- NumPy
- pandas
- Planning Process

- Power BI
- · Problem Solving
- Python
- · Quality Management
- ReactJS
- Real Time Communication
- Real Time Operating System
- · Redis Software
- Redux
- Relational Database Management System
- Representational State Transfer
- · Scalability
- SciPy
- Software Debugging
- Software Development Life Cycle

- Spring
- Statistical Hypothesis Testing
- Statistical Inference
- Statistics
- Tableau Software
- Technical Competency
- Terraform
- · Test Procedure
- Tool Design
- TypeScript
- Unit Testing
- Unix Operating System
- Vue.js
- WordPress
- XML
- Design
- Innovation
- Leadership